Guide to the Joe Negri Collection, 1930-2014 CAM.JNC.2014
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Recordings, IV.
  - Joe Negri Recordings, 1.
    - Mass of Hope Catholic Liturgy in a Jazz Idiom, 2000 (Box 27, Record 1944)
      CD recorded at St. John the Baptist Catholic Church in Erie, PA
    - The Great Years Nov. 11 - #8 (Box 27, Cassette 1945)
      Supertape extended range XR-120
    - Joe Negri-Lou Tracey Song Book (Box 27, Cassette 1946)
      Concertape 30 min. Side 1: Joe Negri Lonely Night That Wonderful Feeling Best of Friends On the Night Side Fred Astaire
      Side 2: Opie Bellas On the Strings of My Heart Be Patient, Alice It Ain't Over 'Til the Fat Lady Sings Joyce Breach: Music is my Best Friend
    - Set II Joe@ Jazz Society, September 24, 1989 (Box 27, Cassette 1947)
      TDK D60 tape Joe with M. Ashby D. LaRocca R. Ryan
      Noted on box: Set II Quality Good Set I Recording Quality not good
    - Joe Negri interview from Pen Radio TV Archives, LaRoche College (Box 27, Cassette 1948)
      TDK D90 cassette tape
    - JSO Pops (Box 27, Cassette 1950)
      TDK D60 cassette JSO Pops w/Joe Negri Tape #2 Scrapple from the Apple Joe & Jeff Manzone
    - Fred Rogers call to Joe, June 10, 1986 (Box 27, Cassette 1951)
      Unmarked white cassette.
    - Joe Negri & Friends Live at Boyce Campus, October 20, 1989 (Box 27, Cassette 1952)
      Maxell 90 cassette. Box labeled Dat Master
    - Negri & Friends at PJS #3 & #4 (Box 27, Cassette 1953)
      Fuji FR II x 90 cassette
    - "The Great Years" (Box 27, Cassette 1954)
      Plain cassette including title and phone number only.
    - An American Made in Paris (International Poetry Forum - Sam Hazo - J. Negri Combo) (Box 27, Cassette 1955)
      Scotch Dynrange 90 cassette.
      Negri Combo - Joe - Guitar Bobby - Piano Dave LaRocca - Bass Lenny Rogers - Drums Eric Kloss Sax/Soprano Sam Hazo Narration
    - Joe Negri Quartet and Sam Hazo (Box 27, Cassette 1956)
      TDK AD-C90 cassette tape
    - Joe Negri Full Interview LaRoche College Archives (Box 27, Cassette 1957)
    - JSO Pops with Joe Negri Tape #1 (Box 27, Cassette 1958)
      TDK D60 cassette.
    - Great Years 1/13 (Box 27, Cassette 1959)
      Maxell 90 cassette tape
    - The Joe Negri Tio on WDTV Pittsburgh 2, 1957 (Box 27, Cassette 1960)
      Includes Lou Mauro (bass), Joe Negri (guitar), Dom Trimarkie (accordian).
      Cassette is inscribed to Joe from Steve Navoyosky
      Reverse side of tape says "Not sure," but an old radio show featuring "George Barnes" etc. (Before my time)
    - Great Years Show #9, November 18, 1990 (Box 27, Cassette 1961)
      Supertape extended range xr-120 cassette.
    - Brockett Memorial, June 5, 1995 (Box 27, Cassette 1962)
      TDK D60 cassette
    - Pgh All Stars @ Mellon Square, June 12, 1972 (Box 27, Cassette 1963)
      High Energy cassette tape
    - Guitar with Love (Box 27, Cassette 1964)
      TDK D90 cassette. Incorrectly labeled 7 Habits of Highly Effective People!
      Side A Guitar w/Love Side B Jazz Cuts
    - Wynton Marsalis Visits Joe Negri's #1563 (Box 27, Cassette 1965)
      TDK AD60 cassette tape.
    - Shep Fields from Orlando, Florida, July 21, 1943 (Box 27, Cassette 1966)
      Kmart 60 minute tape. No case.
    - Mass of Hope (Box 27, Cassette 1967)
      Norelco C-60 Cassette
      Mass of Hope recorded by Steve Zelenko @ Chatham College Chapel Quartet: negri guitar J. Dallas Trombone B. Price Drums B. Boswell Bass Chatham Choir with Lorenzo Malfatti
    - Eartha Kitt & Joe Negri, September 20, 1985 (Box 27, Cassette 1968)
      Recorded Sound LTD cassette.
    - Joe Negri Quartet (Box 27, Cassette 1969)
      Fuji DR-I 90 minute cassette Joe Negri Quartet Jazz Pittsburgh
    - Carmen McRae Granda's Kitchen/Dubs Sombody said and another Spring Joe Negri (Box 27, Cassette 1970)
      TDK SA-X 60 cassette
    - Beat em Bucs (Box 27, Cassette 1972)
      TDK SM10 Cassette Beat em Bucs Benny Benack Music by Joe Negri Words by Sy Bloom
    - Music is my Best Friend, That Wonderful Feeling, Best of Friends, With the Right Person, On the Strings of My Heart (Box 27, Cassette 1973)
      BASF 45 cassette
  - Recordings by Others, 2.
    - Hits 1941-1942 (Box 27, Cassette 1870)
      Maxell UR 90 cassette tape. Side A: 1941 Intermezzo Beat Me Daddy 8 to a Bar 1942 Sleepy Lagoon Everything I Love
      Side B: 1943 Please Think of Me When the Lights Go On Again 1944 Poinciana I'll Walk Alone
    - 1940 - 1941 - 1/2 1942 (Box 27, Cassette 1871)
      JVC GI-60 cassette tape.
      1940 - Enos Donkey Serenade 1941 Intermezzo 1942 Sleepy Lagoon Enos Mister 5 by 5
    - Hits - 1935 - 1936 - 1937 (Box 27, Cassette 1872)
      Maxell UR 90 cassette tape.
      1935 Good Ship Lollipop 1936 With Plenty of Money and You Stomping at the Savoy 1937 Boo Hoo Rosalie 1938 Tipi-Tipi-Tin Love Walked In 1939 Umbrella Man Don't Worry About Me
    - Hits- 1934 - 1935 (Box 27, Cassette 1873)
      Maxell UR 90 Cassette tape.
      Side A 1932 Stardust Your [sic] an old smoothie 1933 Who's Afraid of the Big Bad Wolf
      Side B 1933 By a Waterfall 1934 Jane in January Lost in a Fog 1935 I'm in the Mood for love
    - A. Hits - 1928 - 1929 B. Hits - 1930 - 1931 (Box 27, Cassette 1874)
      Maxell UR 90 cassette.
      Side A 1928 Sonny Boy Marie 1929 Wedding of the Painted Dolls Am I Blue 1930 Dancing with Tears in My Eyes You Brought a New Kind of Love to Me 1931 By the River St. Marie That's Why Darkies Were Born
    - A. Hits - 1924 - 1925 B. Hits - 1926 - 1927 (Box 27, Cassette 1875)
      Maxell UR 90 cassette Tape. Side A: 1924 What'll I Do West of the Great Divide
      1924 [sic] Dina Down by the Vinegar Works
      Side B: 1926 I know that you know Someone to Watch Over Me 1927 Blue Skies Sometimes I'm Happy
    - A. Hits - 1920 - 1921 B. Hits - 1922 - 1923 (Box 27, Cassette 1876)
      Maxell UR 90 cassette
      Side A: 1920 Bright Eyes Rose of Washington Square 1921 Say it with Music Song of Love
      Side B: 1922 A Kiss in the Dark Mister Gallagher & Mr. Shee 1923 Yes We Have No Bananas You've Got to See Momma Every Nite
    - A. Hits - 1916 - 1917 B. Hits - 1918 - 191 (Box 27, Cassette 1877)
      Side A: 1916 Naught, Naughty, Naughty Down Among the Sheltering Pines Pretty Baby Allah's Holiday Way Down in Iowa Poor Butterfly Ireland Must Be heaven What Do You Want to Make Those Eyes At Me There's a Little Bit of Bad in Every Good Little Girl There [sic] Wearing them Higher in Hawaii Yaka Hula Hickey
      Side B: 1918 Hinky Dinky Beautiful Ohio 1919 Oh What a Pal was Mary Irene
    - "Compatible Stereo" (Box 27, Record 1906)
      Audio disc 45 rpm record.
      Two sides labeled "Compatible Stereo"
    - "Material Unknown" (Box 27, Record 1909)
      Audio disc 1 sided disc. 33rd?
    - Napoletana Antologia cronologica della canzone partenopea (Box 1929, Item 1939)
      Album sets, parts 1, 2 & 3, all in Italian.
    - Pittsburghers in Jazz!, 1950 (Box 1929, Cassette 1949)
      Dod Marmarosa Trio w/Tom Madrus (b), Joe Wallace (d); Pitts., 1950. 1) The Night is Young 2) Blue Room 3) Why Was I Born? 4) My Foolish Heart
      Dodo w/Charlie Parker All-stars: Howard McGhee(t), Wardell Gray(ts), B Kessel (g), Red Callendar (b), D Lamond (d); L.A., 1947. 5) Relaxin' at Camarillo
      Side 'B' Eddie Jefferson w/Johnny Morris (tb), Nate Harper (ts), W Harper (p), Bob Boswell (b), Cecil Brooks (d); Pitts., 1952. 1) Body & Soul
      Max Roach Quintet: Stan & Tom Turrentine, Julie Priester (tb), Bob Boswell (b); Europe 1960; 2) Kardouba (w/great bass/drums counter-play!)
- Compositions by Robert McCully, V.
  Original compositions by Robert J. McCully.
  - "The Mann Act" (Box 3, Folder 194-199, Item 197)
    Typed lyrics by Robert J. McCully. 2 pages.
  - "The Cure" (Box 3, Folder 194-199, Item 198)
    Typed lyrics on original skin paper. Marked "Final Version" in red pencil. 4 pages.
  - "If Stephen Foster Had Tried to Sell His Songs Today" (Box 3, Folder 194-199, Item 202)
    Typed script on onion skin. 4 pages.
  - "Those Fabulous Weathermen" (Box 5, Folder 330-334, Item 334)
    Contents interleaved with script to "Yes, We're Going Bananas"
  - "If Stephen Foster Had Tried to Sell His Songs Today" (Box 6, Folder 403-406, Item 403)
    Photocopy of typed script. 4 pages.
    Gammons Show Bob McCully & Joe Negri
  - "Phonecall - Executive Style" (Box 6, Folder 407-416, Item 407)
  - "Chatty Cathy" (Box 6, Folder 407-416, Item 408)
  - "The Baby Sitter" (Box 6, Folder 407-416, Item 409)
    photocopy of typed script. 1 page.
  - "Ajax" (Box 6, Folder 407-416, Item 413)
  - "Bad Breath" (Box 6, Folder 407-416, Item 414)
    Photocopy of typed script. 1 page.
  - "Birthday Present" (Box 6, Folder 407-416, Item 415)
  - "Another Hundred People" (Box 6, Folder 407-416, Item 416)
    photocopy of typed script with handwritten notes. 1 page.
  - "They Hate Us" (Box 6, Folder 407-416, Item 432)
  - "Waiting for the Skybus" (Box 7, Folder 491-501, Item 498)
  - "The Gourmet's Delight" (Box 8, Folder 595-602, Item 599)
    The Establishment Needs Love Too 1969
  - "Charades" (Box 9, Folder 632-642, Item 635)
    Contents originally enclosed in manila folder with the following inscription: 1974 McCully-Negri Lyrics & Comedy Material
  - "Running Gag with Pregnant Girl" (Box 9, Folder 632-642, Item 636)
  - "America, the Beautiful" (Box 9, Folder 632-642, Item 639)
  - "The Baby-sitters" (Box 9, Folder 650-664, Item 651)
  - "Adam and Eve" (Box 9, Folder 650-664, Item 652)
  - "The Public Speaker" (Box 9, Folder 650-664, Item 653)
  - "The Hairdresser" (Box 9, Folder 650-664, Item 656)
  - "Everybody Loves My Baby" (Box 9, Folder 650-664, Item 657)
  - "Chattie Cathy" (Box 9, Folder 650-664, Item 658)
  - "The Real Thing" (Box 9, Folder 650-664, Item 659)
  - "Love, Your Magic Spell is Everywhere" (Box 9, Folder 650-664, Item 660)
  - "Big Business" (Box 9, Folder 650-664, Item 661)
  - "Oakie-Doakie" (Box 9, Folder 650-664, Item 662)
  - "Cops and Robbers" (Box 9, Folder 650-664, Item 663)
  - "The Carwash" (Box 9, Folder 650-664, Item 664)
  - "WhiteHeat" (Box 9, Folder 665-671, Item 665)
  - "The Dairy Farmer" (Box 9, Folder 665-671, Item 666)
  - "The Incident on the 17th Floor" (Box 9, Folder 665-671, Item 667)
  - "Phonecall - Executive Style" (Box 9, Folder 665-671, Item 668)
  - "What's My Favorite Drink?" (Box 9, Folder 665-671, Item 669)
    Typed script. 6 pages.
  - "Dr. Spook" (Box 9, Folder 665-671, Item 670)
  - "The Werner von Roister-Doister Interview" (Box 9, Folder 665-671, Item 671)
  - "Operator, Operator" (Box 9, Folder 705-728, Item 712)
  - "Love, Your Magic Spell is Everywhere" (Box 9, Folder 738-752, Item 748)
    Typed script, 1 page.
    Show - We Dialed the World & It was Busy - 1968 Scripts, Blackouts
  - "The Cure" (Box 9, Folder 738-752, Item 752)
  - "The Story of Frederick Finch" (Box 10, Folder 845-857, Item 850)
    Script typed on onion skin. 4 pages. stapled.
    Joe Negri - KDKA-TV Review Materials "Live on Tape" Carriers
  - "The Cure" (Box 10, Folder 858-859, Item 858)
    Typed title page.
    Contents originally enclosed in a manila folder with the following inscription: An evening without Zsa Zsa Gabor.
- Photos
  - A Celebration of Pittsburgh's Jazz Community, May 19, 1996 (Box 29, Folder 1929, Photos 1929)
    Large format image entitled "A Great Day in Pittsburgh" ceated by In Pittsburgh Newsweekly.
- Awards
  - International Association of Jazz Educators, January 2000 (Box 29, Folder 1930, Item 1930)
- Press Clippings
  - "Negri has proved handy on the guitar", March 2, 2003 (Box 28, Item 1946)
    Article from Pittsburgh Post-Gazette. Two Pages. 3 copies.
  - "Joe Negri Donates Musical Collection to Pitt", February 5, 2001 (Box 28, Item 1947)
    Article from the University of Pittsburgh Chronicle.
  - "Guitarist and Music Educator who introduced generations of children to jazz", August 25, 2013 (Box 28, Item 1948)
    From the website Pittsburgh Muisc History. Long article detailing Negri's career.